<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: character | You have fallen into a pit trap]]></title>
  <link href="http://jsomara.github.com/blog/categories/character/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jsomara.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-27T19:49:53-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jsomara.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan OMara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hero Sheets - The Pathfinder character generator]]></title>
    <link href="http://jsomara.github.com/blog/2013/01/27/hero-sheets-pathfinder-character-sheets/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-27T19:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jsomara.github.com/blog/2013/01/27/hero-sheets-pathfinder-character-sheets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've started working on some software to improve management of <a href="http://www.herosheets.com">Pathfinder
character sheets</a>. I play Pathfinder weekly, and
while the game is quite nice, managing your character is an enormous pain in
the ass. I constantly have to erase and rewrite stuff, people forget to bring
their sheets and nobody knows how to level up. Surprisingly, nobody has really
solved this problem with software.  WOTC provides a pretty nice tool for
electronic character management for D&amp;D 4e, but it is surprisingly lacking in
mobile support.</p>

<p><img src="images/herosheets.png" alt="Hero Sheets logo" /></p>

<p>There isn't even a section of the Pathfinder rulebook that explicitly states
how leveling up works. The rules can be inferred by understanding multiple
sections of the book, but surprisingly there is no flow chart or even simple
paragraph explanation. I hope to fix that! The first goal of Hero Sheets is to
make it simple to create and level up characters. A clear, wizard(hah!)-like
interface and the ability to print a nicely formatted PDF will be a great start
and should hopefully please players everywhere.</p>

<p>I plan on releasing the core rules module as an open source rubygem.
I've mostly been working on the sign up page + blog right now, to help generate
interest, but once the gem is a little more polished I'll toss it up on github.
Even if Hero Sheets isn't successful, maybe the community can make something
interesting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
